const quizQuestions13en = [{
    question:"Argon + hydrogen gas mixtures are suitable for GTAW/TIG of which base material?",
    answers: ["Austenitic stainless steels.",
    "High strength carbon steels.",
    "Low alloy steels.",
    "Aluminium."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding laser beam welding (LBW) it is possible to state that it:",
    answers: ["produces weld beads with a high penetration x width ratio, which prevents welding thin sheets.",
    "demands tighter tolerances for the positioning of the parts.",
    "has a relatively low cost.",
    "is characterized by a high energy conversion efficiency."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"This is an advantage of brazing/soldering process:",
    answers: ["Make it possible to carry out any type of joint (but, lap, Tee, Edge and Corner joint);",
    "The joint can be undone by reheating (except brazing joints);",
    "Less heat and lower temperature are required than in welding by the same heating method;",
    "More heat, but lower temperature are required than in welding by the same heating method."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A welding electric arc is composed of the anodic zone, cathodic zone and arc column. So, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["It is in the arc column that more heat is generated due to its greater length compared to the other zones;",
    "The main functions of the anodic and cathodic zones are to couple the arc to the electrode and to the weld pool and to transfer heat from the arc column to them;",
    "To increase the thermal efficiency of the arc, it is enough to increase the length of the cathodic or anodic zone.",
    "Due to the generation of the predominant heat in the anodic and cathodic zones, the heat generated in these zones is transferred to the electrode and the workpiece with high efficiency."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A welding electric arc is composed of the anodic zone, cathodic zone and arc column. So, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["It is in the arc column that more heat is generated due to its greater length compared to the other zones;",
    "The main functions of the anodic and cathodic zones are to couple the arc to the electrode and to the weld pool and to transfer heat from the arc column to them;",
    "To increase the thermal efficiency of the arc in welding with consumable electrodes, it is necessary to increase heat generation, mainly in the cathodic or anodic zones.",
    "Due to the generation of the predominant heat in its column, the arc presents itself an efficient source of heat."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A welding electric arc is composed of the anodic zone, cathodic zone and arc column. So, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["It is in the arc column that more heat is generated due to its greater length compared to the other zones;",
    "The main functions of the anodic and cathodic zones are to couple the arc to the electrode and to the weld pool and to transfer to them the heat generated in those two zones.",
    "To increase the thermal efficiency of the arc, it is enough to increase the length of the cathodic or anodic zone.",
    "Due to the predominant heat generation in the anodic zone, coupled to the electrode, the arc presents itself an efficient source of heat."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A welding electric arc is composed of the anodic zone, cathodic zone and arc column. So, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["It is in the arc column that less heat is generated, despite its greater length compared to the other zones.",
    "The main functions of the anodic and cathodic zones are to couple the arc to the electrode and to the weld pool and to transfer heat from the arc column to them;",
    "To increase the thermal efficiency of the arc, it is enough to increase the length of the cathodic or anodic zone.",
    "Due to the predominant heat generation in the cathodic zone, coupled to the weld pool, the arc presents itself an efficient source of heat."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the ionization of the elements forming the electric arc, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["The ionization potential of Helium is lower than that of Argon.",
    "All metal vapours require the same energy (work function) to be ionized, unlike gases do.",
    "The ionization potential of each element influences the arc voltage: normally, the higher the ionization potential, the higher the voltage.",
    "If the voltage of a helium arc at 100 A is 30 V and that of an argon arc at the same conditions is 25 V, the helium arc necessarily has a longer arc length."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the welding electric arc, it is possible to state:",
    answers: ["Plasma is an ionized “gas”, composed of electrons and ions, where basically ions are responsible for conducting current.",
    "The electric arc is the passage of a large amount of electric current through an ionized atmosphere, between two electrodes subjected to an adequate difference of potential.",
    "If there were no heat losses from the arc column to the environment, plate and electrode, the arc voltage would be zero.",
    "The electric arc is a perfect converter of electrical energy into thermal energy (no other form of energy is transferred from the arc to the workpiece)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the welding electric arc, it is possible to state:",
    answers: ["Plasma is an ionized “gas”, composed of electrons and ions, where basically ions are responsible for conducting current.",
    "If there were no heat losses from the arc column to the environment, plate and electrode, the arc voltage would be zero.",
    "The main factors controlling the thermal efficiency of the arc are the type of shielding (gas or slag), the characteristics of the shielding gas (ionization potential and heat exchange capacity) and the arc length.",
    "The electric arc is a perfect converter of electrical energy into thermal energy (no other form of energy is transferred from the arc to the workpiece)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"With respect to the temperature distribution in an electric arc, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["The longer the arc length, the greater the power generated and, consequently, the higher the arc temperature.",
    "The centre of the arc (the zone along the axis of the column of the arc) has a higher temperature, which decreases until it reaches the periphery of the arc.",
    "The arc receives heat from the weld pool and the overheated electrode tip to maintain itself.",
    "The arc receives heat from the overheated electrode tip and transmits it to the base metal."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"With respect to the temperature distribution in an electric arc, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["The longer the arc length, the greater the power generated and, consequently, the higher the arc temperature.",
    "Normally, the temperature of an electric arc reaches values above 10000 °C in certain regions, which does not imply that the temperature of the weld pool reaches this value.",
    "The arc receives heat from the weld pool and the overheated electrode tip to maintain itself.",
    "The arc receives heat from the overheated electrode tip and transmits it to the base metal."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In TIG welding of stainless steels, a purge gas used is:",
    answers: ["Argon;",
    "CO2;",
    "a mixture of N2 with H2, the latter varying between 50% and 80%;",
    "an Argon + O2 mixture."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In TIG welding of stainless steels, a purge gas used is:",
    answers: ["CO2;",
    "Nitrogen;",
    "a mixture of N2 with H2, the latter varying between 50% and 80%;",
    "an Argon + O2 mixture."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The following shielding gas is used in TIG welding:",
    answers: ["Argon for all materials.",
    "CO2 for carbon steel only.",
    "a Helium + CO2 mixture;",
    "an Argon + CO2 mixture."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The following shielding gas is used in TIG welding:",
    answers: ["CO2 for carbon steel only.",
    "Nitrogen only for copper and its alloys.",
    "a Helium + CO2 mixture;",
    "an Argon + CO2 mixture."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The following shielding gas is used in TIG welding:",
    answers: ["CO2 for carbon steel only.",
    "a Helium + CO2 mixture;",
    "High purity argon for titanium.",
    "an Argon + CO2 mixture."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Tick the correct alternative, regarding the TIG process (GTAW).",
    answers: ["Autogenous welding (without adding filler metal) is only possible because the electrode is non-consumable.",
    "The arc length (hence the arc voltage) is kept constant due to the use of the non-consumable electrode.",
    "Due to the use of a non-consumable electrode, the welding current does not vary regardless of the power source static characteristic used (Constant Current or Constant Voltage).",
    "Alternating current is never used in the TIG process, because of arc instability."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Tick the correct alternative, regarding the TIG process (GTAW).",
    answers: ["The arc length (hence the arc voltage) is kept constant due to the use of the non-consumable electrode.",
    "No metal-gas reactions occur, making the process clean and easily visible.",
    "Due to the use of a non-consumable electrode, the welding current does not vary regardless of the power source static characteristic used (Constant Current or Constant Voltage).",
    "Alternating current is never used in the TIG process, because of arc instability."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Tick the correct alternative, regarding the TIG process (GTAW).",
    answers: ["The arc length (hence the arc voltage) is kept constant due to the use of the non-consumable electrode.",
    "Due to the use of a non-consumable electrode, the welding current does not vary regardless of the power source static characteristic used (Constant Current or Constant Voltage).",
    "Its main application is in those situations where weld quality is more important than production rate.",
    "Alternating current is never used in the TIG process, because of arc instability."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Tick the correct alternative, regarding the TIG process (GTAW).",
    answers: ["The arc length (hence the arc voltage) is kept constant due to the use of the non-consumable electrode.",
    "Due to the use of a non-consumable electrode, the welding current does not vary regardless of the power source static characteristic used (Constant Current or Constant Voltage).",
    "Alternating current is never used in the TIG process, because of arc instability.",
    "The operation of adding the filler rod is normally manual, but it also can be done by a wire feeder in a mechanized way."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Tick the correct alternative, regarding the TIG process (GTAW).",
    answers: ["It has high thermal efficiency, as the electrical power of the arc is not spent on electrode fusion.",
    "Initially the TIG process used an inert gas only. Currently, inert, active gases or mixtures are used, depending on the type of material to be welded.",
    "The GTAW has low thermal efficiency, as part of the electrical power is dissipated through the electrode to the torch.",
    "Although helium is a more expensive gas than argon, its use instead of argon is justifiable, as it offers more efficient protection, which allows to drastically reduce the gas flow rates used."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Tick the correct alternative, regarding the TIG process (GTAW).",
    answers: ["It has high thermal efficiency, as the electrical power of the arc is not spent on electrode fusion.",
    "An important feature of the TIG process is the excellent control of the energy transferred to the weld pool, due to the independent control of the heat source and the filler metal addition.",
    "Initially the TIG process used an inert gas only. Currently, inert, active gases or mixtures are used.",
    "Although helium is a more expensive gas than argon, its use instead of argon is justifiable, as it offers more efficient protection, which allows to drastically reduce the gas flow rates used."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What will happen to the arc length if, in TIG welding with automatic voltage control (AVC) set to a reference voltage value, the current is increased significantly?",
    answers: ["The arc length remains unchanged, as that's what AVC does.",
    "The arc length will be longer, as the higher is the current, the higher should be the arc voltage.",
    "The arc length will decrease because for a higher current, the same voltage drop maintained by the AVC will correspond to a shorter arc length.",
    "The AVC control adjusts the voltage value to the current value used, so the arc length will increase as well."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"About the MIG/MAG process it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["The spray transfer is the most suitable for welding thick plates, especially in the overhead position.",
    "When welding thick plates in the vertical downward position, it is preferable spray transfer rather than a globular one.",
    "MIG/MAG welding with spray transfer is the most suitable for welding in the vertical position, as it has a similarity with the thermal spray coating technique.",
    "MIG/MAG welding with spray transfer is the most suitable for welding thick plates, due to the higher current (production and penetration), but it is limited to the flat position."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"About the MIG/MAG process it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["In a conventional MIG/MAG equipment (constant voltage power source), an increase in the feed speed increases the current, but the arc length is reduced (if the distance “contact tip - workpiece” remains the same).",
    "The spray transfer is the most suitable for welding thick plates, especially in the overhead position.",
    "In a conventional MIG/MAG equipment (constant voltage power source), an increase in the feed speed increases the current, and, as a consequence, also the arc voltage (if the distance “contact tip - workpiece” remains the same).",
    "By adjusting the wire feed speed and keeping the arc voltage high, the short-circuit transfer can be obtained."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"About the MIG/MAG process it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["The spray transfer is the most suitable for welding thick plates, especially in the overhead position.",
    "In a conventional MIG/MAG equipment (constant voltage power source), an increase in the feed speed increases the current, and, as a consequence, also the arc voltage (if the distance “contact tip - workpiece” remains the same).",
    "In MIG/MAG welding of thick plates in the downward vertical position, it is preferable to adjust the equipment to obtain transfer by short circuit rather than by spray.",
    "By adjusting the wire feed speed and keeping the arc voltage high, the short-circuit transfer can be obtained."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding brazing/soldering, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["The interaction of the metals involved in brazing/soldering with the environment depends on the metals and ambient conditions (gas or brazing flux), but is independent of temperature.",
    "In soldering, as it does not offer significant mechanical strength, it is used only to ensure electrical, thermal and watertight contact.",
    "A brazed joint is achieved only by using the capillary effect.",
    "Generally speaking, a short melting temperature range filler metal is more suitable for large gap joints."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What will happen if, instead of a power source of the Constant Current (CC) static characteristic (SC), one with the SC of the Constant Voltage (CV) type is used for welding with covered electrode?",
    answers: ["It will be difficult to open and to maintain the arc, as the CV type power source has a low no-load voltage (for conventional sources).",
    "The arc length will be kept more constant due to the self-adjusting action offered by the CV type source.",
    "The risk of excessive penetration (even of excessive burn through) will be high, since the SC of the CV type is characterized by higher short-circuit currents.",
    "The risk of the welder suffering an electric shock will be higher, as the CV type power source has a high no-load voltage."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What will happen if, instead of a power source of the Constant Current (CC) static characteristic (SC), one with the SC of the Constant Voltage (CV) type is used for welding with covered electrode?",
    answers: ["The arc length will be kept more constant due to the self-adjusting action offered by the CV type source.",
    "More spatter will be generated, as the CV type power source naturally offers a much higher short-circuit current, which will cause explosions of the metallic bridges during short-circuiting transfer.",
    "The risk of excessive penetration (even of excessive burn through) will be high, since the SC of the CV type is characterized by higher short-circuit currents.",
    "The risk of the welder suffering an electric shock will be higher, as the CV type power source has a high no-load voltage."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What will happen if, instead of a power source of the Constant Current (CC) static characteristic (SC), one with the SC of the Constant Voltage (CV) type is used for welding with covered electrode?",
    answers: ["The arc length will be kept more constant due to the self-adjusting action offered by the CV type source.",
    "The risk of excessive penetration (even of excessive burn through) will be high, since the SC of the CV type is characterized by higher short-circuit currents.",
    "The current would oscillate a lot (in large amplitude) following arc length variations.",
    "The risk of the welder suffering an electric shock will be higher, as the CV type power source has a high no-load voltage."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What will happen if, instead of a power source of the Constant Current (CC) static characteristic (SC), one with the SC of the Constant Voltage (CV) type is used for GTAW/TIG welding?",
    answers: ["It will be difficult to open and to maintain the arc, as the UC type power source has a low no-load voltage (for conventional sources).",
    "The arc length will be kept more constant due to the self-adjusting action offered by the CV type source.",
    "The risk of excessive penetration (even of excessive burn through) will be high, since the SC of the CV type is characterized by higher short-circuit currents.",
    "The risk of the welder suffering an electric shock will be higher, as the CV type power source has a high no-load voltage."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What will happen if, instead of a power source of the Constant Current (CC) static characteristic (SC), one with the SC of the Constant Voltage (CV) type is used for GTAW/TIG welding?",
    answers: ["The arc length will be kept more constant due to the self-adjusting action offered by the CV type source.",
    "It will not be possible to maintain a constant value of the current, as it will oscillate a lot (in large amplitude) following the arc length variations.",
    "The risk of excessive penetration (even of excessive burn through) will be high, since the SC of the CV type is characterized by higher short-circuit currents.",
    "The risk of the welder suffering an electric shock will be higher, as the CV type power source has a high no-load voltage."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What will happen if, instead of a power source of the Constant Voltage (CV) static characteristic (SC), one with the SC of the Constant Current (CC) type is used for GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["Spatter generation will be reduced as the SC of the CC type is characterized by lower short-circuit currents.",
    "Process stability will deteriorate for thicker wires, but improve for thinner wires.",
    "The constant value current will ensure a constant wire melting rate, favouring the stability of the welding process.",
    "It will be impossible to strike the arc due to a limited short-circuit current."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What will happen if, instead of a power source of the Constant Voltage (CV) static characteristic (SC), one with the SC of the Constant Current (CC) type is used for GMAW (MIG/MAG welding)?",
    answers: ["Spatter generation will be reduced as the SC of the CC type is characterized by lower short-circuit currents.",
    "Process stability will deteriorate for thicker wires, but improve for thinner wires.",
    "The constant value current will ensure a constant wire melting rate, favouring the stability of the welding process.",
    "The arc length self-adjustment will not function."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Based on the working principle of thermal cutting, which of the options below is correct?",
    answers: ["Oxyfuel gas cutting is done by the oxidation of iron and expulsion of oxides by the jet of oxygen.",
    "In air carbon arc cutting, the steel is oxidized by compressed air and its oxide is expulsed by the same air jet.",
    "Plasma cutting is not used to cut metals with alloying elements, which produce refractory oxides.",
    "Oxyfuel gas cutting is done by oxidizing the metal and expelling the oxides by the jet of oxygen, so cutting thicknesses are smaller than in the plasma cutting process."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Based on the working principle of thermal cutting, which of the options below is correct?",
    answers: ["In air carbon arc cutting, the steel is oxidized by compressed air and its oxide is expulsed by the same air jet.",
    "Plasma cutting is achieved by melting the metal by a high thermal energy of a constricted columnar arc and expelling the molten metal from the region by high pressure of the plasma jet.",
    "Plasma cutting is not used to cut metals with alloying elements, which produce refractory oxides.",
    "Oxyfuel gas cutting is done by oxidizing the metal and expelling the oxides by the jet of oxygen, so cutting thicknesses are smaller than in the plasma cutting process."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Based on the working principle of thermal cutting, which of the options below is correct?",
    answers: ["In air carbon arc cutting, the steel is oxidized by compressed air and its oxide is expulsed by the same air jet.",
    "Plasma cutting is not used to cut metals with alloying elements, which produce refractory oxides.",
    "In laser cutting, there is no gas jet to expel the material from the cutting region, because it is evaporated due to a high concentration of heat.",
    "Oxyfuel gas cutting is done by oxidizing the metal and expelling the oxides by the jet of oxygen, so cutting thicknesses are smaller than in the plasma cutting process."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Based on the working principle of thermal cutting, which of the options below is correct?",
    answers: ["Oxyfuel gas cutting is done by melting and expelling the molten metal from the region by a high pressure of the flame gases.",
    "In air carbon arc cutting, the molten metal expulsion is done by a compressed air jet. This process can be used for gouging and scrapping (by cutting) also aluminium and its alloys and stainless steel.",
    "Plasma cutting is not used to cut metals with alloying elements, which produce refractory oxides.",
    "Oxyfuel gas cutting is done by oxidizing the metal and expelling the oxides by the jet of oxygen, so cutting thicknesses are smaller than in the plasma cutting process."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"About induction brazing, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["It is a method particularly suitable for metals with high electrical conductivity, such as aluminium.",
    "This heating method is only applicable with a controlled atmosphere.",
    "Induction heating is achieved by means of a high frequency alternating current.",
    "The only drawback of this heating method is that it is slow."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"About induction brazing, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["It is a method particularly suitable for metals with high electrical conductivity, such as aluminium.",
    "A set of coils allows for more heat concentration than a single coil.",
    "This heating method is only applicable with a controlled atmosphere.",
    "The only drawback of this heating method is that it is slow."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding brazing/soldering, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["The interaction of the metals involved in brazing/soldering with the environment depends on the metals and ambient conditions (gas or brazing flux), but is independent of temperature.",
    "A brazed joint is achieved only by using the capillary effect.",
    "Generally speaking, a long melting temperature range filler metal is more suitable for small gap joints.",
    "In high temperature brazing, unlike in brazing and soldering, the chemical bonding (diffusion) between filler metal and base metal is more significant."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Choose the true statement about the electric arc:",
    answers: ["DCEP increases the consumable electrode melting rate, as the anodic region generates more heat than the cathodic one.",
    "The thermal efficiency of an arc welding process is the ratio between the heat input and the total energy generated by the arc (V x I x t). Thus, the greater the arc voltage, for the same current, the greater the thermal efficiency.",
    "The thermal efficiency of spray transfer GMAW is higher than that of short-circuit transfer GMAW.",
    "Voltage drops at the anode and cathode arc connections outweigh the plasma column voltage drop in MIG/MAG welding with the short-circuit transfer."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Choose the true statement about the electric arc:",
    answers: ["The direction of the magnetic blow, caused by the connection effect, changes its direction if the polarity is reversed.",
    "If the helium arc voltage at 100 A is 30 V and an argon arc voltage under the same conditions is 25 V, both consume the same electrical power, since the voltage does not realize the work.",
    "If there were no heat losses from the arc column to the environment, plate and electrode, the arc voltage would be zero.",
    "The plasma jet occurs due to the difference in electromagnetic pressure between the arc coupling on the electrode (higher pressure) and the arc coupling on the workpiece (lower pressure)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"About the metal transfer phenomenon in MIG/MAG welding, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["The Pulsed MIG/MAG welding allows increasing the deposition rate competitively with spray MIG/MAG welding.",
    "The Pulsed MIG/MAG welding competes in terms of deposition rate capacity with the short-circuit MIG/MAG version, but with lower spatter generation.",
    "To promote the occurrence of spray metal transfer, the gas mixture must be richer in CO2.",
    "Globular transfer mode offers such advantages as: absence of spatter (since short circuits do not occur), good bead finishing and an extremely stable arc."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"About the metal transfer phenomenon in MIG/MAG welding, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["The Pulsed MIG/MAG welding allows increasing the deposition rate competitively with spray MIG/MAG welding.",
    "To promote the occurrence of spray metal transfer, the gas mixture must be richer in CO2.",
    "MIG/MAG welding with spray transfer is the most suitable for welding thick plates, due to the higher current (production and penetration), but it is limited to the flat position.",
    "Globular transfer mode offers such advantages as: absence of spatter (since short circuits do not occur), good bead finishing and an extremely stable arc."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"About the metal transfer phenomenon in MIG/MAG welding, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["The Pulsed MIG/MAG welding allows increasing the deposition rate competitively with spray MIG/MAG welding.",
    "To promote the occurrence of spray metal transfer, the gas mixture must be richer in CO2.",
    "Globular transfer mode offers such advantages as: absence of spatter (since short circuits do not occur), good bead finishing and an extremely stable arc.",
    "MIG/MAG welding with short-circuit transfer is the most suitable for root pass welding, due to the low heat input and better control of the weld pool."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the adjustment of parameters in resistance spot welding, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["The time counting in resistance welding processes that use alternating current is done in cycles, depending on the frequency of the electrical network.",
    "Preload (compression) is used to ensure the strength of the joint by pre-strain.",
    "If there is a small weld nugget formation and it is not possible to change the process current, the first indication is to increase the electrode force to increase the spot size.",
    "The current application time must be the same as the force application time."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the adjustment of parameters in resistance spot welding, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["Preload (compression) is used to ensure the mechanical strength of the joint by pre-strain.",
    "Preload (compression) is used to ensure the accommodation of the sheets and adequate electrical resistance between the surfaces.",
    "If there is a small weld nugget formation and it is not possible to change the process current, the first indication is to increase the electrode force to increase the spot size.",
    "The current application time must be the same as the force application time."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"About the FCAW processe it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["There are two basic variations of the FCAW with tubular wires (metal-cored), namely, with and without external gas shielding.",
    "In welding with tubular wires and tubular electrodes, it is highly recommended to use 4 rollers in the semi-automatic welding feed system.",
    "For the FCAW process it is necessary to use wire feeders and torches developed specifically for that.",
    "In FCAW process, by adjusting the wire feed speed and keeping the arc voltage high, the short-circuit and globular transfer modes can be obtained."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"About the FCAW processe it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["There are two basic variations of the FCAW with tubular wires (metal-cored), namely, with and without external gas shielding.",
    "There are two variations of the FCAW process, one in which the protection is ensured by the slag originated from the flux contained inside of the self-shielded wire, and another in which the protection is complemented by an external gas.",
    "For the FCAW process it is necessary to use wire feeders and torches developed specifically for that.",
    "In FCAW process, by adjusting the wire feed speed and keeping the arc voltage high, the short-circuit and globular transfer modes can be obtained."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the welding process with tubular wires (“metal cored”, MCAW) and with flux cored electrodes (FCAW) it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["In the MCAW process all the necessary protection is generated by the flux contained inside of the cored wire.",
    "For the FCAW process it is necessary to use wire feeders and torches developed specifically for that.",
    "In the FCAW process with self-shielded tubular electrodes, all the necessary protection is generated basically by the formation of slag originated by the flux contained inside of the electrode wire.",
    "Because of difficulties in manufacturing tubular wires and electrodes, their diameters are 1.6 mm and higher (while solid wire diameters are usually within the range of 0.6 to 1.6 mm)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the tubular electrode process (FCAW), mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["The bead profile is practically the same as that obtained by the solid wire process, with a cup-shaped melting area.",
    "It is only used with pure CO2 protection, in both gas shielded FCAW and self-shielded FCAW.",
    "It has an advantage of generating less fumes than the solid wire MIG/MAG process.",
    "The process is easier to regulate, because for a given wire speed, the voltage range used is relatively wide, without loss of arc stability and without the need to worry about the metal transfer modes."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is the advantage of robotic MIG/MAG welding over semi-automatic MIG/MAG welding?",
    answers: ["Welding parameters are more stable due to the fact that the contact tip - workpiece distance is kept more constant.",
    "Possibility of welding in all positions.",
    "Time spent for auxiliary operations is reduced.",
    "Welding speed can be higher with the same bead section."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is the advantage of robotic MIG/MAG welding over semi-automatic MIG/MAG welding?",
    answers: ["Possibility of welding in all positions.",
    "Time spent for auxiliary operations is reduced.",
    "Higher welding currents are possible to be used.",
    "The quality is assured on a more constant way."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"An advantage of brazing/soldering with a pre-set filler metal is that:",
    answers: ["there is no need for flux application;",
    "a process control execution is getting easier;",
    "brazing/soldering temperatures may be lower;",
    "less brazing/soldering filler metal is needed."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"An advantage of brazing/soldering with a pre-set filler metal is that:",
    answers: ["there is no need for flux application;",
    "brazing/soldering temperatures may be lower;",
    "it minimizes brazing/soldering defects, such as lack of bonding between base materials;",
    "less brazing/soldering filler metal is needed."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"An advantage of brazing/soldering with a pre-set filler metal is that:",
    answers: ["there is no need for flux application;",
    "brazing/soldering temperatures may be lower;",
    "less brazing/soldering filler metal is needed;",
    "the production rate is higher."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is very common to use pure CO2 shielding gas when welding stainless steels with the FCAW process. Why are oxidation problems not relevant to this case?",
    answers: ["The pure CO2 is a typical shielding gas for welding stainless steels, as was noted, it never creates oxidation problems.",
    "The flux, contained inside of the cored wire, contains some deoxidizers (mainly Si and Mn) that resolve these problems.",
    "The surface of stainless steel is covered by an oxide layer, which protects the steel from any further oxidation, regardless of the oxidation potential of the protective atmosphere.",
    "A high oxidation potential of the protective atmosphere is very beneficial in welding stainless steel because its surface actually needs some oxidation to create a protective oxide layer."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is not a possible application of additive manufacturing?",
    answers: ["Manufacture of a component.",
    "Construction of complementary structures on a component.",
    "Gouging.",
    "Repair of damaged components."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Argon + hydrogen gas mixtures are suitable for GTAW/TIG of which base material?",
    answers: ["High strength carbon steels.",
    "Nickel-based alloys.",
    "Low alloy steels.",
    "Aluminium."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following is an advantage of Plasma Transferred Arc Surfacing?",
    answers: ["Very low dilution.",
    "Added powder material of a low cost.",
    "Very thick deposition layer.",
    "High heat input."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Indicate the correct alternative in relation to the adjustment of MIG/MAG process parameters, keeping the other parameters unchanged:",
    answers: ["As the arc voltage is increased, the current takes on a slightly lower value.",
    "As the distance from the contact tip to the workpiece increases, the arc length also increases.",
    "As the distance from the contact tip to the workpiece increases, the current drops.",
    "As the distance from the contact tip to the workpiece increases, the penetration also increases."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Indicate the correct alternative in relation to the adjustment of MIG/MAG process parameters, keeping the other parameters unchanged:",
    answers: ["As the arc voltage is increased, the current takes on a slightly lower value.",
    "As the distance from the contact tip to the workpiece increases, the arc length also increases.",
    "As the distance from the contact tip to the workpiece increases, the current also increases.",
    "As the distance from the contact tip to the part increases, penetration reduces."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Indicate the correct alternative in relation to the adjustment of MIG/MAG process parameters, keeping the other parameters unchanged:",
    answers: ["As the arc voltage is increased, the current takes on a slightly lower value.",
    "As the pre-set arc voltage is increased, the current takes on a slightly higher value.",
    "As the distance from the contact tip to the workpiece increases, the arc length also increases.",
    "As the distance from the contact tip to the workpiece increases, the penetration also increases."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the electric resistance welding, it is possible to state that:",
    answers: ["In projection welding there is no need to worry about the shunt effect.",
    "Seam welding is achieved by placing spaced lugs on the rotating electrode disc.",
    "Resistance flash welding, contact welding and resistance butt welding are different names for the same resistance welding process.",
    "One of the important advantages of resistance welding machines is that they can be used for different versions of resistance welding (for example, a flash welding machine can be applied for spot welding)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0"},
    {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative about the microstructures of carbon steels:",
    answers: ["Ferrite is a solution of carbon in gamma iron (BCC structure).",
    "Austenite is the interstitial solid solution of carbon in gamma iron (FCC structure).",
    "Austenite is an interstitial solid solution of gamma iron containing carbon at the grain boundary (HC structure).",
    "Martensite is the interstitial solid solution of carbon in gamma iron (FCC structure)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative about the microstructures of carbon steels:",
    answers: ["Ferrite is a solution of carbon in gamma iron (BCC structure).",
    "Austenite is an interstitial solid solution of gamma iron containing carbon at the grain boundary (HC structure).",
    "Ferrite is the solid solution of carbon in alpha iron and delta iron (BCC structure).",
    "Martensite is the interstitial solid solution of carbon in gamma iron (FCC structure)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The presence of pearlite in carbon steels is characteristic:",
    answers: ["only for steels with 0.76% C, regardless of the used cooling rate.",
    "for steels with less than 0.76% C, but only when subjected to rapid cooling.",
    "for steels with 0.76% C, but only when subjected to rapid cooling.",
    "for steels with any amount of carbon, but normally when subjected to slow or moderately slow cooling."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding reheat cracking, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["They can happen during stress relieving heat treatments and/or prolonged work at high temperatures.",
    "They are avoided by preheating, as it prevents diffusion of hydrogen into the HAZ.",
    "They happen preferentially in the HAZ, only in rolled steels and with efforts in the plate thickness direction.",
    "They are avoided if the weld bead is of stainless steel, even if heat treatment is applied."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding reheat cracking, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["They are related to the precipitation of carbides in the HAZ coarse grains region during the stress relief heat treatment.",
    "They are avoided by preheating, as it prevents diffusion of hydrogen into the HAZ.",
    "They happen preferentially in the HAZ, only in rolled steels and with efforts in the plate thickness direction.",
    "They are avoided if the weld bead is of stainless steel, even if heat treatment is applied."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which cast iron will bend before it breaks?",
    answers: ["Nodular cast iron.",
    "White cast iron.",
    "Grey cast iron.",
    "Malleable gray cast iron. "],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Nickel, when added to stainless steels, will ",
    answers: ["increase ductility but decrease impact values;",
    "increase impact values but decrease fatigue resistance;",
    "increase corrosion resistance but decrease thermal conductivity;",
    "increase fatigue resistance and increase electrical conductivity."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"An annealed steel with 0.2% carbon has a microstructure composed of the following constituents:",
    answers: ["Martensite, acicular ferrite and bainite;",
    "Ferrite and pearlite;",
    "Ferrite and martensite;",
    "Partially bainitic microstructure."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"White cast iron serves as the raw material for making:",
    answers: ["malleable cast iron;",
    "low carbon steel;",
    "wrought iron;",
    "ductile iron."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Malleable cast iron is produced from:",
    answers: ["grey cast iron;",
    "pig iron and steel scrap;",
    "white cast iron;",
    "high carbon steel."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Argon + hydrogen gas mixtures are suitable for GTAW/TIG of which base material?",
    answers: ["Austenitic stainless steels.",
    "High strength carbon steels.",
    "Low alloy steels.",
    "Aluminium."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Argon + hydrogen gas mixtures are suitable for GTAW/TIG of which base material?",
    answers: ["High strength carbon steels.",
    "Nickel-based alloys.",
    "Low alloy steels.",
    "Aluminium."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Narrow bead multipass weld of unrestricted carbon steel parts will:",
    answers: ["result in a finer grain structure than in a single pass weld.",
    "cause less distortion than in a single pass weld.",
    "produce higher residual stress than a single pass weld.",
    "ensure higher ductility than a single pass weld."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Copper exhibits as a chemical property:",
    answers: ["a high solubility of many elements;",
    "the impossibility of reaction with nitrogen, hydrogen and halogens;",
    "high oxygen solubility;",
    "low corrosion resistance against many corrosive substances."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Copper exhibits as a chemical property:",
    answers: ["\"a very low oxygen solubility (close to \"\"zero\"\");\"",
    "the impossibility of reaction with nitrogen, hydrogen and halogens;",
    "high oxygen solubility;",
    "low corrosion resistance against many corrosive substances."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Copper exhibits as a chemical property:",
    answers: ["the impossibility of reaction with nitrogen, hydrogen and carbon;",
    "high oxygen solubility;",
    "low solubility of many elements in copper;",
    "low corrosion resistance against many corrosive substances."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Copper exhibits as a chemical property:",
    answers: ["good corrosion resistance against many corrosive substances;",
    "the impossibility of reaction with nitrogen, hydrogen and halogens;",
    "high oxygen solubility;",
    "low solubility of many elements in copper."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Copper exhibits as a chemical property:",
    answers: ["low affinity for oxygen (reacts very slowly with atmospheric oxygen);",
    "the impossibility of reaction with nitrogen, hydrogen and halogens;",
    "low solubility of many elements in copper;",
    "low corrosion resistance against many corrosive substances."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Depending on the lowest operating temperature, welded components operating at cryogenic temperatures can be constructed from:",
    answers: ["low-alloy creep-resistant steels;",
    "martensitic 9 and 12% chromium steels;",
    "structural carbon steels with a carbon content over 0.2%;",
    "CrNi austenitic steels."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Depending on the lowest operating temperature, welded components operating at cryogenic temperatures can be constructed from:",
    answers: ["low-alloy creep-resistant steels;",
    "martensitic 9 and 12% chromium steels;",
    "structural carbon steels with a carbon content over 0.2%;",
    "duplex and superduplex steels."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Depending on the lowest operating temperature, welded components operating at cryogenic temperatures can be constructed from:",
    answers: ["low-alloy creep-resistant steels;",
    "martensitic 9 and 12% chromium steels;",
    "structural carbon steels with a carbon content over 0.2%;",
    "3 and 9% Ni steels."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Depending on the lowest operating temperature, welded components operating at cryogenic temperatures can be constructed from:",
    answers: ["low-alloy creep-resistant steels;",
    "martensitic 9 and 12% chromium steels;",
    "structural carbon steels with a carbon content over 0.2%;",
    "low-carbon low-alloy structural steels."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Under high magnification, graphite in nodular cast iron is seen as:",
    answers: ["rounded spheres;",
    "rounded flakes;",
    "elongated flakes;",
    "rectangular shapes."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The weldability of a dissimilar joint between carbon steel and stainless steel is dependent on which of the following?",
    answers: ["The base material compositions;",
    "The level of carbon in the base materials.",
    "The difference in the melting temperatures of these steels;",
    "Their magnetic characteristics (magnetic blow!)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The weldability of a dissimilar joint between carbon steel and stainless steel is dependent on which of the following?",
    answers: ["The filler metal composition.",
    "The level of carbon in the base materials.",
    "The difference in the melting temperatures of these steels;",
    "Their magnetic characteristics (magnetic blow!)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The weldability of a dissimilar joint between carbon steel and stainless steel is dependent on which of the following?",
    answers: ["The dilution ratio.",
    "The level of carbon in the base materials.",
    "The difference in the melting temperatures of these steels;",
    "Their magnetic characteristics (magnetic blow!)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding fine-grained steels, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["In welding of steels with refined granulometry, a region of grain growth occurs in the ZAC due to the thermal cycle. This grain growth is irreversible.",
    "All fine-grained steels have martensitic ZAC, due to the greater hardenability of a fine-grained material;",
    "The heat treatment for grain refining is done by austenization and rapid cooling (in water or oil), to prevent grain growth;",
    "The addition of alloy elements refines the grain structure of the steel as it favours heterogeneous nucleation."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding fine-grained steels, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["In welding of steels with refined granulometry, a region of grain growth occurs in the ZAC due to the thermal cycle. This grain growth is irreversible.",
    "All fine-grained steels have martensitic ZAC, due to the greater hardenability of a fine-grained material;",
    "The heat treatment for grain refining is done by austenization and rapid cooling (in water or oil), to prevent grain growth;",
    "Grain refining increases the strength of the material, as it decreases the average distance travelled by dislocations."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding fine-grained steels, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["In welding of steels with refined granulometry, a region of grain growth occurs in the ZAC due to the thermal cycle. This grain growth is irreversible.",
    "All fine-grained steels have martensitic ZAC, due to the greater hardenability of a fine-grained material;",
    "The heat treatment for grain refining is done by austenization and rapid cooling (in water or oil), to prevent grain growth;",
    "It is possible to refine steel grains through cold working followed by recrystallization heat treatment."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following elements encourages the formation of austenite?",
    answers: ["Chromium.",
    "Molybdenum.",
    "Silicon.",
    "Manganese."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following elements encourages the formation of austenite?",
    answers: ["Chromium.",
    "Molybdenum.",
    "Silicon.",
    "Nickel."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following elements encourages the formation of austenite?",
    answers: ["Aluminium.",
    "Titanium.",
    "Vanadium.",
    "Cobalt."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following elements encourages the formation of austenite?",
    answers: ["Aluminium.",
    "Titanium.",
    "Vanadium.",
    "Carbon."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following elements encourages the formation of austenite?",
    answers: ["Chromium.",
    "Zirconium.",
    "Niobium.",
    "Nitrogen."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the factor influencing the coarsening grains in welded joints of steels?",
    answers: ["The exchange of direct current for alternating current.",
    "The presence of diffusible H2.",
    "A ferritic structure in the base metal.",
    "An increase in the number of passes."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Microalloying of weld metal with vanadium has a positive effect: ",
    answers: ["enabling the formation of a fine-grained structure;",
    "reducing the ductile-brittle transition temperature;",
    "increasing corrosion resistance;",
    "improving cold formability."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Wear protection is achieved by:",
    answers: ["cathodic protection;",
    "galvanizing;",
    "painting;",
    "surfacing."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Wear protection is achieved by:",
    answers: ["cathodic protection;",
    "galvanizing;",
    "painting;",
    "nitriding."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Ferritization in the HAZ is a characteristic of:",
    answers: ["austenitic steels;",
    "ferritic steels;",
    "duplex steels;",
    "martensitic steels."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which is the only strengthening method that simultaneously increases both strength and toughness?",
    answers: ["Solid solution hardening.",
    "Precipitation hardening.",
    "Cold working.",
    "Grain refinement."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Inter crystalline corrosion in an austenitic stainless steel is most likely to happen in:",
    answers: ["slow cooled weldment (sensitization);",
    "quickly cooled weldment;",
    "low carbon stainless steel (< 0,02%);",
    "stainless steels containing additions of Ti and Nb. "],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Inter crystalline corrosion in an austenitic stainless steel is most likely to happen in:",
    answers: ["high carbon stainless steel;",
    "quickly cooled weldment;",
    "low carbon stainless steel (< 0,02%);",
    "stainless steels containing additions of Ti and Nb. "],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Inter crystalline corrosion in an austenitic stainless steel is less likely to happen in:",
    answers: ["high chromium stainless steel (e.g. grade 310/310S); ",
    "slow cooled weldment (sensitization);",
    "high carbon stainless steel;",
    "stainless steels with no Ti and Nb additions. "],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Weld joints of Cr-Ni austenitic steel are prone to:",
    answers: ["cold crack formation;",
    "formation of cold cracks, if preheating is not applied;",
    "hot crack formation;",
    "lamellar crack formation."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Weld joints of Cr-Ni austenitic steel are prone to:",
    answers: ["cold crack formation;",
    "formation of cold cracks, if preheating is not applied;",
    "delta phase precipitation;",
    "lamellar crack formation."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Among the problems caused by a low temperature in steels, we can point out:",
    answers: ["Hardness reduction;",
    "Reduction of the creep resistance;",
    "Reduction of the ductile-to-brittle transition temperature - DBTT;",
    "Reduction of yield strength."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Among the problems caused by a low temperature in steels, we can point out:",
    answers: ["Hardness reduction;",
    "Reduction of the creep resistance;",
    "Reduction of the ductile-to-brittle transition temperature - DBTT;",
    "Reduction of toughness."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Among the problems caused by the low temperature in steels, we can point out:",
    answers: ["Hardness reduction;",
    "Reduction of the creep resistance;",
    "Reduction of the ductile-to-brittle transition temperature - DBTT;",
    "Reduced ductility."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Among the problems caused by a low temperature in steels, we can point out:",
    answers: ["Hardness reduction;",
    "Reduction of the creep resistance;",
    "Reduction of the ductile-to-brittle transition temperature - DBTT;",
    "Reduction of ultimate strength."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What corrosion type are aluminium and its weldable alloys sensitive to?",
    answers: ["Selective Corrosion.",
    "Intergranular corrosion.",
    "Pitting corrosion.",
    "Fretting Corrosion."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which elements are responsible for hardenability in martensitic stainless steels?",
    answers: ["Molybdenum and vanadium.",
    "Chromium and carbon.",
    "Molybdenum and carbon.",
    "Chromium and vanadium."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following nickel-based alloys has copper in it?",
    answers: ["Incoloy.",
    "Monel.",
    "Inconel.",
    "Hastelloy B."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"\"The alloy group of materials called \"\"Hastelloys\"\" contain:\"",
    answers: ["nickel and copper;",
    "nickel and niobium;",
    "nickel and molybdenum;",
    "nickel and titanium."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which properties will increase with the addition of nickel to steel or alloys?",
    answers: ["Hardness.",
    "Resistance to hot cracking.",
    "Ferritic structure stabilization.",
    "Reduction of the thermal expansion coefficient."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which properties will increase with the addition of nickel to steel or alloys?",
    answers: ["Impact properties (lower the ductile-to-brittle transition temperature - DBTT).",
    "Resistance to hot cracking.",
    "Ferritic structure stabilization.",
    "Reduction of the thermal expansion coefficient."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following is widely used for gas turbines?",
    answers: ["Incoloy alloys.",
    "Nichrome alloys.",
    "Nimonic alloys.",
    "Hastelloy alloys."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"},
    {
    question:"This is an example of dynamic loading:",
    answers: ["the own weight of the structural elements;",
    "the overload on the floors;",
    "the weight of rotating mechanical equipment;",
    "gusts of wind."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"In a welded joint that will be subjected to fatigue, it is recommended to:",
    answers: ["use materials of very high mechanical resistance, with a small plastic region;",
    "use materials of low mechanical resistance, with a small plastic region;",
    "smooth the fillet weld toes;",
    "use autogenous welding processes (without filler metal)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"How would it be possible to increase the fatigue strength of aluminium alloy butt welds?",
    answers: ["Brushing the aluminium oxide layer.",
    "Performing peening.",
    "Using the TIG welding process whenever possible.",
    "Applying backing."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About notches, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["During welding, only internal notches occur, eg slag inclusions;",
    "Stress concentration caused by a notch does not lead to a reduction in fatigue strength, but it does reduce the yield point;",
    "Notches are typical imperfections of autogenous welding (mainly because of an incompletely filled groove);",
    "They can change the fracture mechanism from ductile to cleavage in a material working above the ductile-brittle temperature."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the S-N curves, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["They present low values for the low cycle fatigue regime;",
    "They demand a large amount of experimental data;",
    "The S-N curve is the most used model to determine the residual life of a workpiece with a crack developed in service;",
    "The S-N curve is composed of three fragments: 1 - stress reduction; 2 - stress stabilization and 3 - sudden stress drop (fatigue failure)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the S-N curves, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["They present low values for the low cycle fatigue regime;",
    "They are based on Wöhler curves;",
    "The S-N curve is the most used model to determine the residual life of a workpiece with a crack developed in service;",
    "The S-N curve is composed of three fragments: 1 - stress reduction; 2 - stress stabilization and 3 - sudden stress drop (fatigue failure)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the resistance of materials, it can be said:",
    answers: ["The dimensions of metal construction components, deflection and stability depend on the applied loads, the section area and the type of material used;",
    "The material strength limit is normally much higher than the yield point due to the recrystallization phenomenon that occurs during the tensile test;",
    "The actual rupture strength is much lower than the rupture strength recorded by the tensile test;",
    "The strength of materials is affected by several factors: temperature, type of tensile testing machine, among others."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the resistance of materials, it can be said:",
    answers: ["When designing any structure, it is first necessary to use the principles of static loading to determine the external and internal forces acting on its elements;",
    "The material strength limit is normally much higher than the yield point due to the recrystallization phenomenon that occurs during the tensile test;",
    "The actual rupture strength is much lower than the rupture strength recorded by the tensile test;",
    "The strength of materials is affected by several factors: temperature, type of tensile testing machine, among others."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the resistance of materials, it can be said:",
    answers: ["The objective of the theory of resistance of materials is to determine the forces originated from the actions and to verify the type of material to be used and dimension the section to resist these forces;",
    "The material strength limit is normally much higher than the yield point due to the recrystallization phenomenon that occurs during the tensile test;",
    "The actual rupture strength is much lower than the rupture strength recorded by the tensile test;",
    "The strength of materials is affected by several factors: temperature, type of tensile testing machine, among others."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Local buckling strength of aluminium open profile elements can be increased: ",
    answers: ["by welds with a high reinforcement (which serves as a stiffener);",
    "by welded stiffeners;",
    "by applying welded joints transversally to the direction of the acting compressive stresses;",
    "using permanent backing strips (which serve as a stiffener)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Local buckling strength of aluminium open profile elements can be increased: ",
    answers: ["by welds with a high reinforcement (which serves as a stiffener);",
    "by increasing the plate thickness;",
    "by applying welded joints transversally to the direction of the acting compressive stresses;",
    "using permanent backing strips (which serve as a stiffener)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Local buckling strength of aluminium open profile elements can be increased: ",
    answers: ["by welds with a high reinforcement (which serves as a stiffener);",
    "by applying welded joints parallel to the direction of the acting compressive stresses;",
    "by applying welded joints transversally to the direction of the acting compressive stresses;",
    "using permanent backing strips (which serve as a stiffener)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"A plate is welded from both sides and has a 10% lack of penetration in the weld centre. This plate is purely flexion loaded around the weld axis. About this situation it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["The tensile stress on the surface will be greater than the compressive stress on the opposite surface of the joint;",
    "The compressive stress on the surface will be greater than the tensile stress on the opposite surface of the joint;",
    "Both the tensile and compressive stresses from both sides of the joint will be increased by 5% each;",
    "It does not affect the resulting stresses (tensile and compressive) on the joint surfaces."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"A partial penetration double sided butt weld is statically loaded in tension. The load carrying section is determined from:",
    answers: ["the thickness of the thinner plate;",
    "the thickness of the thicker plate;",
    "the thickness of the thinner plate minus the unwelded (unmelted) region;",
    "the thinner plate thickness plus the weld metal reinforcement on both sides."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"\"What is the difference between the terms \"\"dynamic loading\"\" and \"\"cyclic loading\"\"?\"",
    answers: ["They are absolute synonyms.",
    "\"Usually they are used synonymously, although \"\"dynamic loading\"\" refers to short period (instantaneous) loading, while \"\"cyclic loading\"\" applies to long period (continuous) loading.\"",
    "\"\"\"Dynamic loading\"\" is a single compressive or tensile action, while \"\"cyclic loading\"\" is repetitive loading.\"",
    "\"\"\"Dynamic loading\"\" is a single tensile-compression loading cycle, whereas \"\"cyclic loading\"\" is of repetitive type.\""],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"This shall be established during the design of a weldment:",
    answers: ["Values of the essential variables of the WPS to be developed.",
    "The most recommended welding positions.",
    "NDT methods to be applied.",
    "The critical joints and the acceptance criteria."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"It is NOT a principle of ISO 9001 (Quality Management System, Requirements):",
    answers: ["Customer focus;",
    "Process approach;",
    " (Continual) Improvement;",
    "To maintain the same level of quality already achieved."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"To start a fire, the following element(s) must be present:",
    answers: ["only one element, namely, a combustible material;",
    "two essential elements: combustible material and oxygen;",
    "three essential elements: combustible material, oxygen and ignition;",
    "four essential elements: combustible material, oxygen, ignition and air supply."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"To extinguish a fire:",
    answers: ["it is enough to remove one of three essential elements: combustible material or oxygen or heat;",
    "it is enough to remove two of three essential elements: combustible material, oxygen, heat;",
    "all three essential elements (combustible material, oxygen and heat) must be removed;",
    "at first, the oxygen must be removed and then the combustible material."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"A fire to continue, the following element(s) must be present:",
    answers: ["only one element, namely, a combustible material;",
    "two essential elements: combustible material and oxygen;",
    "three essential elements: combustible material, oxygen and heat;",
    "four essential elements: combustible material, oxygen, heat and air supply."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"According to ISO 9001 (2015), the quality management system (QMS) shall be based on the 7 principles; this is one of them:",
    answers: ["Effort in production: To produce more and more, until quantity is transferred into quality;",
    "Customer focus: to meet customers’ current and future requirements and expectations;",
    "Individual responsibility: Everyone is responsible for its tasks. The overall responsibility lies with the leaders.",
    "Competitiveness: To aim to be more successful than others."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"According to ISO 9001 (2015), the quality management system (QMS) shall be based on the 7 principles; this is one of them:",
    answers: ["Effort in production: To produce more and more, until quantity is transferred into quality;",
    "Leadership: to stimulate employees in achieving the organization’s unified objectives;",
    "Individual responsibility: Everyone is responsible for its tasks. The overall responsibility lies with the leaders.",
    "Competitiveness: To aim to be more successful than others."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"According to ISO 9001 (2015), the quality management system (QMS) shall be based on the 7 principles; this is one of them:",
    answers: ["Effort in production: To produce more and more, until quantity is transferred into quality;",
    "Engagement of People: to retain competent employees, encouraging continuous enhancement of their knowledge and skills;",
    "Individual responsibility: Everyone is responsible for its tasks. The overall responsibility lies with the leaders.",
    "Competitiveness: To aim to be more successful than others."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"According to ISO 9001 (2015), the quality management system (QMS) shall be based on the 7 principles; this is one of them:",
    answers: ["Effort in production: To produce more and more, until quantity is transferred into quality;",
    "Process approach: to manage and control an overall manufacturing system (input – activities – output) focusing in individual interrelated processes;",
    "Individual responsibility: Everyone is responsible for its tasks. The overall responsibility lies with the leaders.",
    "Competitiveness: To aim to be more successful than others."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"According to ISO 9001 (2015), the quality management system (QMS) shall be based on the 7 principles; this is one of them:",
    answers: ["Effort in production: To produce more and more, until quantity is transferred into quality;",
    "Continuous Improvement: to embrace new opportunities and to adapt to new market situations;",
    "Individual responsibility: Everyone is responsible for its tasks. The overall responsibility lies with the leaders.",
    "Competitiveness: To aim to be more successful than others."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"According to ISO 9001 (2015), the quality management system (QMS) shall be based on the 7 principles; this is one of them:",
    answers: ["Effort in production: To produce more and more, until quantity is transferred into quality;",
    "Evidence-based Decision Making: to make a decision based on data and analysis;",
    "Individual responsibility: Everyone is responsible for its tasks. The overall responsibility lies with the leaders.",
    "Competitiveness: To aim to be more successful than others."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"According to ISO 9001 (2015), the quality management system (QMS) shall be based on the 7 principles; this is one of them:",
    answers: ["Effort in production: To produce more and more, until quantity is transferred into quality;",
    "Relationship Management: to interact with interested parties such as customers, employees and suppliers;",
    "Individual responsibility: Everyone is responsible for its tasks. The overall responsibility lies with the leaders.",
    "Competitiveness: To aim to be more successful than others."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is correct to say in relation to the functions of a quality management system (QMS) of a company that applies welding:",
    answers: ["To ensure that its personnel are aware of the relevance and importance of their activities and how they contribute to achieving quality objectives;",
    "Choose the most productive welding process for the preferred use in the company;",
    "Choose the welding process that offers the best quality to replace other welding processes with that one;",
    "The QMS helps maintaining the subordination discipline: everyone is responsible only for their individual tasks."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is correct to say in relation to the functions of a quality management system (QMS) of a company that applies welding:",
    answers: ["To maintain appropriate records of the education, training, skill and experience of its personnel;",
    "Choose the most productive welding process for the preferred use in the company;",
    "Choose the welding process that offers the best quality to replace other welding processes with that one;",
    "The QMS helps maintaining the subordination discipline: everyone is responsible only for their individual tasks."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is correct to say in relation to the functions of a quality management system (QMS) of a company that applies welding:",
    answers: ["To maintain necessary records to provide evidence that the process used and the resulting product meet requirements;",
    "Choose the most productive welding process for the preferred use in the company;",
    "Choose the welding process that offers the best quality to replace other welding processes with that one;",
    "The QMS helps maintaining the subordination discipline: everyone is responsible only for their individual tasks."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is correct to say in relation to the functions of a quality management system (QMS) of a company that applies welding:",
    answers: ["Determine requirements not stated by the customer but necessary for the specified or intended use;",
    "Choose the most productive welding process for the preferred use in the company;",
    "Choose the welding process that offers the best quality to replace other welding processes with that one;",
    "The QMS helps maintaining the subordination discipline: everyone is responsible only for their individual tasks."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"The ISO 3834 standard - \"\"Quality requirements for fusion welding of metallic materials\"\" is developed in such a way that:\"",
    answers: ["when applied, it allows to reduce welding costs;",
    "when applied, it allows to increase the production rate;",
    "when applied, it allows the production of imperfections-free welds;",
    "it is independent of the type of welded construction carried out."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"The ISO 3834 standard - \"\"Quality requirements for fusion welding of metallic materials\"\" is developed in such a way that:\"",
    answers: ["when applied, it allows to reduce welding costs;",
    "when applied, it allows to increase the production rate;",
    "when applied, it allows the production of imperfections-free welds;",
    "it defines the quality requirements for welded constructions no matter where the fabrication takes place: in a factory, or in a shipyard or in a construction site."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"The ISO 3834 standard - \"\"Quality requirements for fusion welding of metallic materials\"\" is developed in such a way that:\"",
    answers: ["when applied, it allows to reduce welding costs;",
    "when applied, it allows to increase the production rate;",
    "when applied, it allows the production of imperfections-free welds;",
    "it provides guidelines that allow the manufacturer to achieve a capability to produce constructions that meet defined requirements."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"The ISO 3834 standard - \"\"Quality requirements for fusion welding of metallic materials\"\" is developed in such a way that:\"",
    answers: ["when applied, it allows to reduce welding costs;",
    "when applied, it allows to increase the production rate;",
    "when applied, it allows the production of imperfections-free welds;",
    "it provides the necessary basis for the audit of the manufacturer's capability in terms of welding activities."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"The ISO 3834 standard - \"\"Quality requirements for fusion welding of metallic materials\"\" identifies measures that are applicable:\"",
    answers: ["when a company needs to set limits for the size of weld imperfections;",
    "when a company needs to optimize the production line to avoid raw material and time losses;",
    "in contractual situations: specification of welding quality requirements;",
    "for resolving conflict situations between the manufacturer and its customer."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"The ISO 3834 standard - \"\"Quality requirements for fusion welding of metallic materials\"\" identifies measures that are applicable:\"",
    answers: ["when a company needs to set limits for the size of weld imperfections;",
    "when a company needs to optimize the production line to avoid raw material and time losses;",
    "by manufacturers: establishment and maintenance of welding quality requirements;",
    "for resolving conflict situations between the manufacturer and its customer."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"The ISO 3834 standard - \"\"Quality requirements for fusion welding of metallic materials\"\" identifies measures that are applicable:\"",
    answers: ["when a company needs to set limits for the size of weld imperfections;",
    "when a company needs to optimize the production line to avoid raw material and time losses;",
    "by committees drafting manufacturing codes or application standards: specification of welding quality requirements;",
    "for resolving conflict situations between the manufacturer and its customer."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"The ISO 3834 standard - \"\"Quality requirements for fusion welding of metallic materials\"\" identifies measures that are applicable:\"",
    answers: ["when a company needs to set limits for the size of weld imperfections;",
    "when a company needs to optimize the production line to avoid raw material and time losses;",
    "by organizations assessing welding quality performance, e.g., third parties, customers, or manufacturers;",
    "for resolving conflict situations between the manufacturer and its customer."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following welding and cutting processes can generate nitrogen oxides above the permissible limit?",
    answers: ["Air plasma cutting.",
    "SMAW/MMA welding.",
    "Electroslag welding.",
    "Oxy-acetylene welding."],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the items below contains a subject that has NOTHING to do with Quality Management, Control and Assurance?",
    answers: ["Customer focus, Product, Compliance with customer requirements.",
    "Leadership and Commitment, Product, Labour Salary.",
    "Customer satisfaction, Realistic quality objectives, Emphasis on prevention.",
    " Understanding interested party’s needs, Resources, Continuous improvement."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The main cause of residual stresses in welding is:",
    answers: ["the heat treatment cycles after welding;",
    "wrong welding techniques;",
    "errors in the groove preparation;",
    "welded joint metal phase transformations due to welding cycles."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The main cause of residual stresses in welding is:",
    answers: ["the heat treatment cycles after welding;",
    "wrong welding techniques;",
    "errors in the groove preparation;",
    "shrinkage on cooling of differently heated and plasticized regions during the welding operation."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Lower residual stresses are observed in:",
    answers: ["welding procedures that use higher heat input;",
    "welding procedures that use lower heat input;",
    "welding procedures that use the technique of pre-fixing parts before welding to minimize distortion;",
    "the cases of removal of auxiliary mounting devices (fixtures) immediately after welding."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the main constituent of the thick white smoke produced when arc welding galvanized steel?",
    answers: ["Zinc acid fumes.",
    "Galvanized smoke.",
    "Zinc oxide fumes.",
    "A mixture of zinc vapours and ozone."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"An auditor of a welding company, in order to perform well his tasks, has the obligation to:",
    answers: ["verify evidence that the procedures provided by the management system are being followed;",
    "develop quality management procedures for the company, before starting the audit;",
    "only present the report with non-conformities, never issuing observations to improve the company's quality system (he is an auditor and not a consultant);",
    "check the financial health of the company."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"An auditor of a welding company, in order to perform well his tasks, has the obligation to:",
    answers: ["prepare and present an audit plan prior to the start of the audit;",
    "develop quality management procedures for the company, before starting the audit;",
    "only present the report with non-conformities, never issuing observations to improve the company's quality system (he is an auditor and not a consultant);",
    "check the financial health of the company."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Why is it recommended to use sampling techniques in quality processes, on welded joints, produced repeatedly?",
    answers: ["Sampling techniques are more reliable than inspecting 100% of manufactured products.",
    "Companies prefer the sampling technique, as these techniques allow them to cover up potential failures from customers.",
    "It is impractical, for technical, economic or time reasons, to carry out inspections on all manufactured products.",
    "Customers prefer products from companies that use sampling technique control."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"About the Welding Operating Factor (WOF) it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["The WOF is the ratio of clock hours to arc hours and is a variable that determines the energy consumption.",
    "Manual processes have higher WOF because the welder is always busy in one of his activities, unlike operators in automatic processes;",
    "The reduction of WOF in automatic processes is always beneficial, as it allows reducing electricity costs;",
    "The WOF is the ratio of arc hours to clock hours and is a variable that determines, basically, the cost of labour."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"About the Welding Operating Factor (WOF) it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["The WOF is the ratio of clock hours to arc hours and is a variable that determines the energy consumption.",
    "Manual processes have higher WOF because the welder is always busy in one of his activities, unlike operators in automatic processes;",
    "The reduction of WOF in automatic processes is always beneficial, as it allows reducing electricity costs;",
    "Semi-automatic and automatic processes have higher WOF because they have longer open arc time compared to manual processes."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the economic factors of arc welding processes, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["Due to the higher currents used, the FCAW process has a higher cost of electricity per kg of deposited metal;",
    "The use of intermittent welds, whenever possible, is an option to reduce the amount of deposited metal, increasing productivity.",
    "The reduction of the welding operating cycle together with the increase of the deposition rate, guarantee a reduction of the welding time and consequently allow a greater productivity;",
    "In the GMAW process, the greater the stick-out for the same wire feed speed, the greater the deposition rate."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"}]
    
    ;